A Guide to the "Many More: Women in Architecture, 1978-1988," Exhibit Files and Panels, 1950-1998
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
"Many More: Women in Architecture, 1978-1988," Exhibit Files and Panels, 1987-1988
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms2000-084
10 boxes; 50.2 cu. ft.
The collection contains correspondence, announcements, clippings, release forms, transcripts of the Exhibit Committee Meeting and an index of the accepted entries, regarding the preparation and organization of the exhibit.
Library and Archives of the American Institute of Architects
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
The "Many More: Women in Architecture, 1978-1988," Exhibit Files and Panels were donated to Special Collections in 1991 and March 2000.
Biographical Information
"Many More: Women in American Architecture, 1978-1988" premiered on May 15, 1988 at the 1988 American Institute of Architects National Convention and Design Exposition in New York City. It was sponsored by the AIA's Women in Architecture Committee in response to the exhibit "That Exceptional One: Women in American Architecture, 1888-1988."
"Many More" illustrated the strength and diversity of contributions of women in the architectural profession. All building types, practice specialties, and geographic regions were solicited for representation. It was created as a showcase of the work done between 1978 and 1988 by women currently then in practice in the United States. The scope of this exhibit was to "illustrate the strength and diversity of women's current contribution to the architectural profession through architecture, urban design and planning, landscape architecture, computer applications, preservation, historical analysis, criticism, renderings, and research".
Scope and Content
The collection contains correspondence, announcements, clippings, release forms, transcripts of the Exhibit Committee Meeting and an index of the accepted entries, regarding the preparation and organization of the exhibit. The guidelines for the jury members whom selected the projects are of particular interest.
The collection also contains both entries accepted (77 projects) and entries not accepted (67 projects) for the exhibit. Submitted projects contained an entry form that collected fundamental data regarding the project, such as: Project Title, Location, Architect or Firm, Owner or Developer, Engineers, General Contractor, Completion Date, specific use of the building, brief project description, and statement of the role the woman played in the project. In addition each project was documented by sketches, drawings, photographs, or slides, submitted by the designer.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged by material type.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
"Many More: Women in Architecture, 1978-1988," Exhibit Files and Panels, 1987-1988 was sponsered by the AIA's Women in Architecture Committee in response to the exhibit "That Exceptional One: Women in American Architecture, 1888-1988."
Contents List
- Exhibited Entries, 1988. (Box 1)
- Exhibited Entries, 1988. (Box 2)
- Exhibited Entries, 1988. (Box 3)
- Exhibited Entries, 1988. (Box 4)
- Exhibited Entries, 1988. (Box 5)
- Exhibited Entries, 1988. (Box 6)
- Exhibited Entries, 1988. (Box 7)
- Release Forms - Miscellaneous, 1988. (Box-folder 8:1)
- Archive Retention Permissions, 1988. (Box-folder 8:2)
- Barney, Carol Ross, 1987. (Box-folder 8:3)
- Entry Announcement, 1988. (Box-folder 8:4-5)
- Entry Forms, 1988. (Box-folder 8:6-7)
- Exhibit Information, 1988. (Box-folder 8:7A)
- Jury Tally Sheets, 1988. (Box-folder 8:8)
- Legal Counsel, 1988. (Box-folder 8:9)
- Packing Box List, 1988. (Box-folder 8:10)
- Release Forms (A-G), 1988. (Box-folder 8:11)
- Release Forms (H-M), 1988. (Box-folder 8:12)
- Release Forms (R-Z), 1988. (Box-folder 8:13)
- Richardson, Heidia., AIA. (Box-folder 8:14)
- Screening Committee Meeting Transcript, 1988. (Box-folder 8:15)
- Pontius, Geraldine. (Box-folder 8:16)
- Quinn and Searl. (Box-folder 8:17)
- Index (Box-folder 8:18)
- Agrait, Laura Cardero—Clínica Las América in Puerto Rico (Box-folder 8:19)
- Bakker, Margaret E. - Residence for Alan & Day Weitzman, Annapolis, Maryland (Box-folder 8:20)
- Barney, Carol Ross - Glendale Heights Post Office, Illinois (Box-folder 8:21)
- Batter, Janice Kay - Lighthouse, La Jolla, California (Box-folder 8:22)
- Bennett, Melissa B. - West Roxbury Branch Library, Boston, MA (Box-folder 8:23)
- Binder, Rebecca L. - Fischer Residence, Playa del Rey, CA (Box-folder 8:24)
- Brown, Andrea Clark - Brown Residence, Naples, Florida (Box-folder 8:25)
- Brown, Daphne E. - Providence Center for Child Development, Anchorage, Alaska (Box-folder 8:26)
- Brown, Daphne E. - Family support center, Kodiak, Alaska (Box-folder 8:27)
- Burns, Norma De Camp - Chatham County Social Services Building, Pittsboro, NC (Box-folder 8:28)
- Cary, Mary C. - Eklutna Water Treatment Facility, Chugach, Alaska (Box-folder 8:29)
- Cass, Heather W. - Conservatory and Botanical Gardens, Maryland (Box-folder 8:30)
- Chang, Pao-Chi - Fire Station CF-13, Chicago, Illinois (Box-folder 8:31)
- Cherry, Edith - Belen High Gymnasium, Belen, New Mexico (Box-folder 8:32)
- Christidis, Thaleia - De Beache, Bridgehampton, N.Y. (Box-folder 8:33)
- Coffin, Christie - Science Facilities Complex, University of Oregon, Eugene, OR (Box-folder 8:34)
- Cole, Doris - Damson & Greenage, Boston, MA (Box-folder 8:35)
- Dougherty, Betsey Olenick - Architectural studio, Newport Beach, CA (Box-folder 8:36)
- Edelman, Judith - Columbus Green Apartments, New York, N.Y. (Box-folder 8:37)
- Ellis, Eugenia Victoria - Lake Eola Park restroom Facilities, Orlando, Florida (Box-folder 8:38)
- Ericson, Elizabeth S. - The Children's Hospital, Boston, MA (Box-folder 8:39)
- Frewen-Wuellner, Cynthia - Luxembourg Office Park, Overland Park, KS (Box-folder 8:40)
- Geddis, Barbara L. - Douglas gardens Campus, New York, N.Y. (Box-folder 8:41)
- Glitsch, Val - Kipling Townhouse, Houston, Texas (Box-folder 8:42)
- Gong, Janny T. - Tower 45, New York, N.Y. (Box-folder 8:43)
- Goody, Joan - 99 Summer Street, Boston, MA (Box-folder 8:44)
- Gould, Amy - Jefferson Patterson Park & Museum, St. Leonard, MD (Box-folder 8:45)
- Hann, Marlys - Stone house, New York, N.Y. (Box-folder 8:46)
- Hansen, Fani Danadjieva - University of California, Medical Center, Sacramento, CA (Box-folder 8:47)
- Hatch, Helen Davis - Crocker Center, Boca Raton, Florida (Box-folder 8:48)
- Hebald-Heymann, Mango - Simi Valley Dental Group, Simi Valley, CA (Box-folder 8:49)
- Hood, Bobbie Sue - Macondray Terrace, San Francisco, CA (Box-folder 8:50)
- Ingraham, Elizabeth Wright - Vista Grande Community Church, Colorado Springs, CO (Box-folder 8:51)
- Kane, Mary Bulota - Green Ranch, Reno Nevada (Box-folder 8:52)
- Keane, Jan - George M. Low Center for Industrial Innovation, New York, N.Y. (Box-folder 8:53)
- Lawson, Elizabeth -Murphy Hall Chapel Renovation, Glenside, PA (Box-folder 8:54)
- Leers, Andrea P. - Cabot's Stains Corporate Headquarters, Newburyport, MA (Box-folder 8:55)
- Leers, Andrea P. - Hanscom Airfield maintenance Building, Bedford, MA (Box-folder 8:56)
- Legge, Diane–Arlington Park, Arlington heights, Illinois (Box-folder 9:57)
- Legge, Diane–The Boston Globe, Satellite Newspaper Facility, Billerica, MA (Box-folder 9:58)
- Lewis, Michele – Gould Residence, Great Neck, N.Y. (Box-folder 9:59)
- Litman-Cleper, Aviva - Clovis Community Hospital, Clovis, CA (Box-folder 9:60)
- London, Gabrielle (missing material) (Box-folder 9:61)
- Maxman, Susan (missing material) (Box-folder 9:62)
- McCabe-Miele, Gigi – Stremmel House, Sanibel, Florida (Box-folder 9:63)
- Mickley, Pamela Ann – Calvary Church of the Nazarene, Annandale, Virginia (Box-folder 9:64)
- Mitchell, S., Dell – Yankee Bank, Boston, MA (Box-folder 9:65)
- Moore, Ava – Plaza Medical Building, Kansas City, MO (Box-folder 9:66)
- Moore, Karen A. – Registry of Motor Vehicles, Worchester, MA (Box-folder 9:67)
- Padjen, Elizabeth – Peabody Institute Library, Danvers, MA (Box-folder 9:68)
- Piomelli, M. Rosaria- Landmark Condominium, Tarrytown, N.Y. (Box-folder 9:69)
- Quinn, Kathryn – Roth/Wilner House, Wayne, Illinois (Box-folder 9:70)
- Rothman, Martha – Beth Israel Hospital, Boston, MA (Box-folder 9:71)
- Rowe, Judy L. – Oakland YMCA, Oakland, CA (Box-folder 9:72)
- Searl, Linda – La Barge Townhouse Remodeling, Chicago, Illinois (Box-folder 9:73)
- Sherman, Patricia C. – Farm at New England Inn, Intervale, NH (Box-folder 9:74)
- Siegel, Margot – Los Angeles Airport Cooling Tower, Los Angeles, CA (Box-folder 9:75)
- Simon, Cathy – College eight, Santa Cruz, CA (Box-folder 9:76)
- Siris, Jane – Ulick/Flamino Loft, New York, N.Y. (Box-folder 9:77)
- Som, Helen Woo – DLI-63, Seoul, South Korea (Box-folder 9:78)
- Stavi, Jacqueline – Borel Financial Center, San Mateo, CA (Box-folder 9:79)
- Stavi, Jacqueline – 300Third Street, San Francisco, CA (Box-folder 9:80)
- Stevens, Mary Otis – Pool Pavilion & related Additions, Chestnut Hill, MA (Box-folder 9:81)
- Thompson, Elizabeth – Renovations, 2 apartments, New York, N.Y. (Box-folder 9:82)
- Weese, Cynthia – Chestnut Place Apartments, Chicago, IL (Box-folder 9:83)
- Weinstein, Amy – 317 Massachusetts Ave., Washington D.C. (Box-folder 9:84)
- Weinzapfel, Jane – Park Street Station Entry and Exit Structures, Boston, MA (Box-folder 9:85)
- Weinzapfel, Jane – Martin Center for Engineering Design, Cambridge, MA (Box-folder 9:86)
- White, Ortrude – Spring Hill, Durham, NC (Box-folder 9:87)
- Wightman, Lisa – Oberline Drive Residence, Glendale, CA (Box-folder 9:88)
- Wilks, Barbara E. – Roosevelt recreation Center, Baltimore, MD (Box-folder 9:89)
- Williams, Terri S. – Bank of Mississippi, Columbus, Mississippi (Box-folder 9:90)
- Willis, Beverly – San Francisco Ballet Association Building, CA (Box-folder 9:91)
- Willis, Beverly – Margaret Hayward Park Playground Building, San Francisco, CA (Box-folder 9:92)
- Winderman, Allyne – Stillwell Hotel, Los Angeles, CA (Box-folder 9:93)
- Wood, Joan – Doerfer Residence, Brookline, MA (Box-folder 9:94)
- Wrightson, Denelle – Northeast Police Substation, Dallas, Texas (Box-folder 9:95)
- 63/105 – Single Family Residence, Upstate, New York (Box-folder 9:96)
- Beattie, Roseanne AIA – American Association for the Advancement of Science, Washington, DC (Box-folder 9:97)
- Binder, Rebecca L., AIA – Pacific Townhouses, Santa Monica, CA (Box-folder 9:98)
- Brown Hiaryorie, Eliason – Washburn Country Courthouse, Shell Lake, WI (Box-folder 9:99)
- Cahnman, Sheila Fogel AIA – US Postal Service Cafeteria, Chicago, Illinois (Box-folder 9:100)
- Caplan, Sherry T. – Hill & Barlow, Boston, MA (Box-folder 9:101)
- Chang Pao-Chi AIA – Pembroke Area Family Health, Pembroke, Illinois (Box-folder 9:102)
- Chorno, Lia M. – Upper Bucks Nursing Center, Milford Township, PA (Box-folder 9:103)
- Coats, Mary – Coats Building, Jackson, TN (Box-folder 9:104)
- Cole, Doris – Haberkorn Renovation, Weston, MA (Box-folder 9:105)
- Diamond, Katherine AIA – Lawndale Civic Center, Lawndale, CA (Box-folder 9:106)
- Diamond, Katherine – Commonwealth Elementary school, Los Angeles, CA (Box-folder 9:107)
- Digeronimo, Suzanne – Lincoln Tunnel Emergency Garage, Weehawken, New Jersey (Box-folder 9:108)
- Diminic, Jasenka – Marguerite Terrace, Brookline, MA (Box-folder 9:109)
- Eckert, Cody A. – New Era Bank, Somerset, N.J. (Box-folder 9:110)
- Frederick, Jocelyn L. – Health Care Center, Evanston, Illinois (Box-folder 9:111)
- Frewen – Wuellner, Cynthia – Frewen Architect Offices, Kansas City, MO (Box-folder 9:112)
- Geise Carolyn, D. - Child Study and Treatment Center, Tacoma, WA (Box-folder 9:113)
- Geise Carolyn, D. - Barbara Allan, Seattle, WA (Box-folder 9:114)
- Glitsch, Val - Zvonkovic House, Houston, Texas (Box-folder 9:115)
- Gong, Janny T. - Americas Tower, New York, N.Y. (Box-folder 9:116)
- Goode, Cardyn H. - The Strain House, Indianapolis, IN (Box-folder 9:117)
- Hastings, L. Jane - Remodeled Darden Residence, Seattle, WA (Box-folder 9:118)
- Hastings, L. Jane - Ken Holland Residence, Kodiak, AL (Box-folder 9:119)
- Hatch, Helen D. AIA - Memphis Marriott Hotel, Memphis, Tennessee (Box-folder 9:120)
- Jhones, Kate - Academy Hill Townhouses, Hudson, New York (Box-folder 9:121)
- Kapila, Malti R. - Cobblefield, White Plains, NY (Box-folder 9:122)
- Kapila, Malti R. - Stone Oaks, Hartsdale, NY (Box-folder 9:123)
- Kim, Soo - Project title with held at owners request for security reasons (Box-folder 10:124)
- Kinsey, Caryl A. - Residence in Dix Hills, Dix Hills, NY (Box-folder 10:125)
- Kleine, Linda AIA - Silver Vien, Los Angeles, CA (Box-folder 10:126)
- Lari, Sussan - American Ultramar Limited, Tarrytown, NY (Box-folder 10:127)
- Lari, Sussan - Indiana University, Bloomington, IN (Box-folder 10:128)
- Lawson, Elizabeth AIA - Dormitory Dining/Kitchen, Bryn Mawr, PA (Box-folder 10:129)
- Leach, Margo - Leach house, Chadds Ford, PA (Box-folder 10:130)
- Litman-Cleper, Aviva - South Terminal Remodeling project, San Francisco Int'l Airport (Box-folder 131)
- Marcus, Lily AIA - Williams Island Tower 'D', North Miami Beach, Florida (Box-folder 10:132)
- Marcus, Lily AIA - Trump Organization Offices, New York, NY (Box-folder 10:133)
- Manevich, Martha Bil - Cancer Center, Framingham union Hospital, Framingham, MA (Box-folder 10:134)
- McCabe-Miele, Gigi - 1833 North Orchard Street, Chicago, Illinois (Box-folder 10:135)
- Milosevich, Branka - Branka Milosevich residence of 61 reserve street #5, Boston, MA (Box-folder 10:136)
- Moore, Ava - Children's Mercy Hospital Canopy (Box-folder 10:137)
- Nelson, Linda Lee - Hopewell Center, Inc., Anderson, IN (Box-folder 10:138)
- Oakes, Julia Harden - Crescent Heights Apartments, West Hollywood, CA (Box-folder 10:139)
- Perdomo, Maureen - Hooper, Hataway, Price, Beuche & Wallace, Ann Arbor, MI (Box-folder 10:140)
- Perdomo, Maureen - Hepps #1, Kalamazoo, MI (Box-folder 10:141)
- Poirier, Myrna - The Ryland Group, Columbia, MD (Box-folder 10:142)
- Saul, Leslie S. - Offices of Combined Jewish Philanthropies, Boston, MA (Box-folder 10:143)
- Shad, Margaret - one Prudential Plaza, Chicago, IL (Box-folder 10:144)
- Shao, Margaret - Christ Hospital and Medical Center, Oak Lawn, IL (Box-folder 10:145)
- Sherman, Patricia AIA - Straw Hill, Manchester, N.H. (Box-folder 10:146)
- Sklarek, Norma - Terminal One LAX, Los Angeles, CA (Box-folder 10:147)
- Smith, Marion B. - State Veterans Nursing Home, Cape Girardeau, MO (Box-folder 10:148)
- Som, Helen W. AIA - Polk Office Building, San Francisco, CA (Box-folder 10:149)
- Thompson, Elizabeth - Residence, Orient, Long Island, New York (Box-folder 10:150)
- Van Liere, Patricia - Arizona Heart Institute, phoenix, AZ (Box-folder 10:151)
- Yu, Jane AIA - Renovations Elmer Holmes Bobst Library New York University (Box-folder 10:152)
- Yu, Jane AIA - Geller House, Cedarhurst, N.Y. (Box-folder 10:153)